- 哈喽，雷蒙德？
- 比那好多了
- HeIIo, Raymond?
- Even better.
我是罗伯特……
I'm Robert...
他弟兄
the brother.
唔，嗨。
我是卡萝・马歇尔
WeII, hi.
I'm CaroI MarshaII
哈姆国际真空清洁设备的
from Humm Vac CIeaning
Systems InternationaI.
- 请进
- 谢谢
- PIease, come in.
- Thank you.
- 你一定是雷蒙德了
- 是的，嗨
- You must be Raymond.
- Yeah, hi.
我昨晚喝你妻子谈好
过来演示操作我们的设备
I spoke to your wife Iast night about
coming by to demonstrate our system.
哦，是的。是的，吸尘器
Oh, right. Yeah, the vacuum.
我以为她说我们
不需要新的吸尘器的
I thought she said we didn't need
a new vacuum cIeaner.
是的，她说了。我记得，
因为那是她说
Yeah, she did. I remember, because
it was right before she toId me
我得上哪拿什么之前说的
I have to go pick up
something from somewhere.
哦，你不明白我说的，是不是？
Oh. You didn't happen
to catch any of that, did you?
对不起
Sorry.
是的，不过我们昨晚谈的时候，
事情好像进展得很顺利
Yeah, so when we spoke Iast night,
things did seem pretty hectic.
所以，因为我碰巧经过附近，
So, since I happened
to be in the neighborhood,
我想也许现在可以
过来向你们
I wondered if now
might be a good time
演示一下哈姆真空设备
是多么神奇，
to come show you how wonderfuI
the Humm Vac is
并且送上这把赠品毛球刷
and to offer you
this compIimentary Iint brush.
是吗，我不知道。
我妻子说我真的不能――
Yeah, I don't know. My wife says
I'm reaIIy not supposed--
行了，雷蒙德，
这是赠品（恭维）
Come on, Ray,
it's compIimentary.
可以吗，罗伯特？
May I, Robert?
不会疼的
This won't hurt a bit.
欧呜。酷
Eww. CooI.
归你了，感谢你的耐心
And that is yours
for being a good patient.
谢谢
Thank you.
你真温柔
You were very gentIe.
哦这里，还有给你的
Oh here, I have one
for you too.
干什么？
你吓死我了
What are you doing?
You scared the heII out of me.
这是什么？
What is that?
这是你保证会喜欢的东西
This is something
that you're gonna Iove.
哈姆真空吸
The Humm Vac Aspirate.
- 什么？你买的？
- 是的
- What? You bought this?
- Yep.
你听到我在电话上
跟那个女士说了
You heard me teII
the Iady on the phone
咱们不需要吸尘器
that we do not need
a vacuum cIeaner.
我知道，可结果证明咱们需要
I know, but it turns out
we reaIIy do.
她给我看了一大堆土
She showed me aII the dirt.
你让她进来了？
等等――等一等
You Iet her in here?
Wait-- wait a minute.
这个推销员女士有多漂亮？
How good Iooking
was this saIesIady?
你知道吗？
她非常漂亮
You know what?
She was quite good Iooking.
可我不怕说出来
But I'm not afraid to say that
因为这机器也一样好
'cause that's how good
this machine is.
就算换个丑男人我也买了！
I wouId've bought this
from an ugIy man!
你整个一冤大头
You are such a sucker.
我不能抗拒完美的产品！
A sucker for
a great product!
听到这哈姆哈姆的声音了吗？
You hear that hum?
全封闭的四马力马达
That's a fuIIy-insuIated,
four horsepower motor.
这个，夫人，是干净的声音！
That, madame,
is the sound of cIean!
“用途多用吗？”你问。
看看这个
''Is it versatiIe?'' you ask.
Check this out.
这整块地方我只用了30秒
I did this whoIe
section in 30 seconds.
扁吸头，卟！完事！
Crevice attachment,
boom! Done!
好吧，看，这很好
AII right, Iook,
that's very nice.
等等！看看这个
Wait a minute! Watch this.
你不会相信的
You're not gonna beIieve this.
这些坐垫看起来够干净了……
These piIIows
seem cIean enough...
就肉眼看来！
to the naked eye!
如果是普通吸尘器，
In a reguIar vacuum,
吸力还比不上
there's not enough suction
power to pick up
鸡毛掸子
aII the dirt that
the beater bar kicks up.
雷，关掉。
我昨天吸过了
Ray, turn it off.
I vacuumed there yesterday.
就算你昨天吸四五次，
用你的老吸尘器
You couId have vacuumed five times
yesterday with your oId vacuum.
雷，你想把我的坐垫怎么样？
Ray, what are you
doing to my piIIow?
耐心点，亲爱的。
看着
Patience, my dear.
Look.
哈姆真空的吸力高50倍
the Humm Vac has up
to 50 times more suction power.
吸掉灰尘、死皮、
宠物毛，只要是你有的，
It puIIs up dust, dead skin,
pet dander, what have you,
然后存到这个水罐里
deposits it aII into
this water reservoir.
- 不用袋子！
- 好吧，听着
- No bags!
- Okay, Iisten.
把她叫回来退了！
You're caIIing her back
and returning it!
还是持怀疑态度，巴伦太太？
StiII skepticaI, Mrs. Barone?
唔……
WeII...
我不想吓你
I don't want to frighten you.
不过这里
But this
是你的老吸尘器漏掉的东西
is what your oId vacuum
has been missing.
喔
Wow.
这就是我们说的
“喔元素”
It's what we caII
''The Wow Factor.''
他们把这也加进了设备的设计
They buiId it
right into the system.
这就是你家人呼吸的污浊物
This is the fiIth
that your famiIy's been breathing.
现在，你只要把它
倒进下水道
Now, you just dump it
right down the drain.
这真的很惊人
That is pretty amazing.
是的。现在，让我教你怎么清理窗帘
Yeah. Now, I'II show you
how to do the drapes.
你要清理窗帘？
You're gonna do the drapes?!
不不，小傻瓜，是哈姆真空清理窗帘
No no, siIIy, the Humm Vac's
gonna do the drapes.
我只负责接受表扬
I'm just gonna take the credit.
我这辈子从没对你
I have never been
more attracted to you
这么着迷过
in my entire Iife.
想试试吗？
Wanna try?
- 好的
- 你的第一次
- Okay.
- Your first time.
我嫉妒你
I envy you.
哈喽，亲爱的！
HeIIo, dears!
- 嗨，玛丽
- 嗨
- Hi, Marie.
- Hi.
我从窗口经过，
I was passing by my window
然后忍不住看了看屋子里
and I couIdn't heIp
seeing into your window.
然后我注意到
你们买了新吸尘器
And I noticed,
you bought a new vacuum.
这机器戏东西的能力太惊人了，玛丽。
而且不用袋子！
It's amazing what this thing
picks up, Marie. And no bags!
不用袋子！
No bags!
- 真高兴这事成了
- 什么意思？
- I am so gIad this worked out.
- What do you mean?
那个推销女士打电话
告诉我
When the saIesIady
caIIed me and toId me
她有自笤帚以来
最重大的清洁发明的时候，
she had the greatest cIeaning
innovation since the broom,
我立刻想到了你
I immediateIy
thought of you.
- 你叫她来的？
- 当然了！
- You sent her over here?
- Of course!
我可不知道
I did not know that.
唔，你们俩继续
WeII, you two enjoy.
我永远不想干涉家务活
I wouId never want
to interfere with housework.
现在是跟你说说
Now might be a good time
to teII you about
免费的桉树空气清新剂的时候了
the free eucaIyptus
room freshener.
把鞋子脱掉，我刚刚吸过那的！
Take your shoes off,
I just vacuumed up there!
嗨，玛丽
Hi, Marie.
- 哈喽，亲爱的
- 我有没有打搅你？
- HeIIo, dear.
- Am I interrupting anything?
哦不。我只是把富兰克的裤子
再改大些
Oh no. I'm just Ietting
Frank's pants out again.
现在就看天意了
It's in God's hands now.
你知道，玛丽，
You know, Marie,
我心里有点事，
something was bothering me
我只想问问你
and I just wanted
to ask you about it.
当然了，亲爱的。
什么事？
Of course, dear.
What is it?
唔，
WeII,
你知道今天下午，
you know this afternoon,
你说那个女推销员
when you said
that the saIesIady
告诉你她有多么好的
新清洁工具的时候……
toId you that she had this
great new cIeaning device...
你立刻想到了我
you immediateIy
thought of me.
为什么？
Why was that?
不，真的，玛丽。为什么？
No, reaIIy, Marie. Why?
这是耍人的问题吗？
Is this a trick question?
不。只是你好像总是暗示
No. It just seems Iike
you're aIways impIying
我没把家保持干净
that I don't keep a cIean house.
唔，现在你有帮手了
WeII, now you have a IittIe heIp.
可是你不觉得你
不需要买个哈姆真空
But you didn't feeI
the need to buy a Humm Vac.
唔，那机器是给那些……
WeII, that machine
is for peopIe--
就像是……
it's Iike...
如果你腿出毛病了，
你就会需要拐杖
if you have a bad Ieg,
then you need crutches.
而你的腿很好？
And your Iegs are fine?
那么说这屋子里没灰了？
So there's no dirt
in this house?
我在当然没有了
Not since I've Iived here.
- 真的吗？
- 嗯嗯
- ReaIIy?
- Mm-hmm.
- 谢谢
- 好的
- Thank you.
- Okay.
哦！你把你的新吸尘器拿来了
Oh! You brought
your new vacuum here.
需要我教你怎么用吗？
Do you need me
to show you how to use it?
不，我知道怎么用。
我只想让你知道点事
No, I know how to use it.
I just want to show you something.
你要吸我的屋子？
You're going
to vacuum my house?
你知道，我家也许看起来
You know, my house
might appear
是比你的乱了点
to be a bit more
cIuttered than yours.
不过好吧，偶尔有些碎渣子、
And aII right, there's
the occasionaI crumb,
脏盘子。我不是说没有脏东西
dirty dish. I'm not
saying there's no dirt.
是的，是有，不过每个房子里都一样
Yeah, there is,
but that's every house.
每所房子都有灰尘，
玛丽，即便是这里
Every house has dirt,
Marie, even this one.
唔，我得说，
我想你――
WeII, I must say,
I think you're going--
让让，玛丽！
Excuse me, Marie!
这就是所谓的
This is what we caII
货物集散地
a high-traffic area.
逆着地毯绒了
You're going against the nap.
从没有人告诉过你绒纹吗？
Did anyone ever
teach you about nap?
好吧
Okay.
咱们来看看
Let's take a Iook
我们乐意称为的
at what we Iike to refer to as
“喔元素”
''The Wow Factor.''
这水看起来很干净
That water
Iooks very cIean.
喔
Wow.
唔，让――让我――
让我再――
WeII, I-Iet-- Iet me just--
让我试试沙发地下，好吗？
Iet me try under
the couch, okay?
好了
There we go.
这底下肯定脏得厉害
It can get pretty
nasty under here.
好了
Okay.
该死
Damn it.
是我眼花了还是
这水看起来真得更干净了？
Is it me, or does that
water Iook even cIeaner?
唔，
WeII,
我才刚学用这个，所以……
I'm stiII kinda getting
the hang of this, so...
你得明白，亲爱的，
You have to
understand, dear,
吸尘器不能打扫屋子，
that vacuums
don't cIean houses.
人才是打扫屋子的
PeopIe cIean houses.
你知道，也许我没把这个
You know, maybe
I just didn't have this
完全伸进去，就是这样
pushed aII the way in,
that's it.
唔，欢迎继续
WeII, you're weIcome
to keep going.
也许是个好的练习机会
It's probabIy good practice.
我的裤子呢，玛丽？
我要冻死了！
Where are my pants, Marie?
I'm freezing here!
哦，来了，弗兰克！
Oh, coming, Frank!
你都弄了一头大汗了
You've worked up
quite a sweat.
等我回来
给你拿点凉的喝
When I come back, I'II bring
you something cooI to drink.
- 嘿，你做什么呢？
- 把你鞋给我
- Hey, what are you doing?
- Give me your shoes.
什么？
你干什么？
What?
What are you doing?
你和孩子们今天去沙池了，是不是？
You and the kids were in the sandbox
this morning, weren't you?
是的，怎么了？哦，不，
帕克的猫也去了？
Yeah, what? Oh, no,
did Parker's cat get in there?
快点！
我需要灰尘！
Come on!
I need some dirt!
我要让你妈永远闭上嘴！
I'm gonna shut
your mother up once and for aII!
你要用土堵上她的嘴？
Are you gonna fiII
her mouth with dirt?
不！用地毯
No! On the rug.
她会看到她像所有其他人
一样需要这个吸尘器
She's gonna see she needs
this vacuum Iike anybody eIse.
拜托，先解开鞋带！
Come on, untie it first!
哦，快点！
把另一只拿来
Oh, come on!
Give me the other one.
哦不
Oh no.
该死，偏偏今天你不做猪了！
Damn it, the one day
that you're not a pig!
我想你气出毛病来了
I think you're
getting a IittIe nuts here.
塑料。是塑料的！
It's pIastic.
It's pIastic!
连她的土都不是土！
Even her dirt's not dirt!
你知道这是什么吗？
这就是个白痴狗屁吸尘器！
You know what it is?
It's this stupid vacuum cIeaner!
我叫你不要买的！
I toId you not to buy it!
不不不不。
不！不！停下！
No no no no.
No! No! Stop it!
嘿！
Hey!
嚷嚷什么呢？
What's with aII the yeIIing?
我不认为能黛比拉找得到土
I don't think Debra
couId find any dirt.
好了，好吧，这里没土，你赢了！
Okay, aII right, there's
no dirt here, you win!
我只是受不了你
让我觉得自己是个糟糕的人，
But I am sick of you making
me feeI Iike a bad person
就因为我没照你那样
照看我的房子！
because I don't keep my house
exactIy the way you do!
干净的房子并不是
世界上最重要的东西
A cIean house is not the most
important thing in the worId.
你知道谁会这么说？
没有条理的人
You know who says that?
A messy person.
好吧。你也许无法相信，玛丽，
AII right. As hard as this
is for you to beIieve, Marie,
我的确想保持一个整洁的房子
I do Iike to keep a neat house.
我只是不会把每一点空余时间
都用来打扫它！
I'm just not going to spend
every spare minute cIeaning it!
没有空余时间。
你有一家人要照顾
There are no spare minutes.
You have a famiIy to care for.
是的，我要！
我关心我的家人
Yes, I do!
I care for my famiIy.
我花时间爱他们，
而不是给他们消毒
I spend my time enjoying them,
not steriIizing them.
- 你是说我不爱我的家人了？
- 不，那不是――
- You're saying I don't Iove my famiIy?
- No, that's not--
因为世上没有比家人更让我爱的了
Because there's nothing in the worId
I Iove more than my famiIy.
放松！
Easy!
不，只是这房子太干净太……
No, it's just that this
house is so cIean and so...
有条理了
arranged.
这可不是世上最温馨的地方
It's not exactIy
the warmest pIace in the worId.
- 你怎么能这么说？
- 唔，我是说，拜托
- How couId you say that?
- WeII, I mean, come on.
塑料沙发套
PIastic sIipcovers.
这是为了保护沙发面
That's to protect
the uphoIstery.
是保护了沙发面，
可你想过别人的感受是什么吗？
So it protects the uphoIstery, but
how do you think it makes peopIe feeI?
又热又粘乎
Hot and sticky.
特别是夏天
家人聚集的时候
EspeciaIIy in the summer
when I'm in my aII-together.
我说，感谢上帝赐予沙发套
I say, thank the Lord
for the sIipcovers.
哦，得了吧，雷！
Oh, come on, Ray!
你老是拿沙发套编笑话
You make jokes about those
sIipcovers aII the time.
你笑我的沙发套？
You joke
about my sIipcovers?
没可能。不，这不是我的作风
No way.
No, that's not my styIe.
你刚刚是怎么说
塑料、
What did you just say
about the pIastic
化妆间还有客人用的毛巾的？
and the powder room
and the guest toweIs?
跟我说说，雷蒙德
TeII me, Raymond.
就是，你知道，就好像，
Just, you know, it's Iike,
那些咱们从没用过的瓷器
there's the china
that we never use
和从没碰过的客人用毛巾
and there's toweIs
that we never touch.
就好像你把所有东西都留着
It's Iike you're
saving everything
等一个从没出现过的时刻
for a speciaI occasion
that hasn't happened yet.
他说得没错
He's right.
那些带金边的小毛巾是
干什么的？
What are those IittIe toweIs
with the goId fringe for?
等教皇过来用咱们楼下的马桶？
For when the Pope comes over
here to use the downstairs can?
- 安静
- 我要用了它们
- Be quiet.
- I'm using 'em.
不，你不能。
你高兴了，雷蒙德？
No, you're not!
Are you happy now, Raymond?
行了，妈，不是什么大不了的
Come on, Ma,
it's not a big deaI.
我来告诉你，雷蒙德
Let me teII you
something, Raymond.
你们俩兄弟小时候，
成天在土里头打滚
When you boys were IittIe, you were
aIways outside in the dirt.
然后把这当公交车站一样
到处乱踩
Then you'd tromp through
here Iike it was a bus station.
然后罗伯特长的一双大脚，
And Robert with his gigantic feet,
就像屋里养了匹马
it was Iike having
a horse in the house.
不，这可不是笑话
No, it was not funny.
不，我只有这样
才能保护这个地方
No, it was aII I couId do
to take care of this pIace.
- 嗨
- 把鞋子脱了！
- Hi.
- Take off your shoes!
- 哈？
- 脱下来！这不是马房
- Huh?
- Take them off! You're not in a barn.
照她说的做，
我们给你胡萝卜吃
Do what she says,
we'II give you a carrot.
怎么了？
What's going on?
看到了，玛丽？
这就是我说的
You see, Marie?
This is what I'm taIking about.
你眼里只关心房子干净，
You're so obsessed
with the house being cIean,
看看你对你儿子做了什么
Iook what you're doing
to your son.
好吧。好吧
AII right. Fine fine.
把鞋子穿回去，
想怎么奔就怎么奔
Put your shoes back on and gaIIop
around here aII you want.
- 什么？
- 穿回去
- What?
- Put them back on.
是的，同时检查一下
你的脚什么时候过期
Yeah, and check the expiration
date on your feet.
- 你做什么？
- 大家都想让我改变，
- What are you doing?
- Everyone wants me to change,
我可以改变
I can change.
- 我这就把套子拿掉
- 那我们坐哪？
- I'm taking the covers off.
- Where are we gonna sit?
你们可以就坐在沙发上
You can sit right here
on the couch
因为我不在乎这些事了
'cause I don't care about
these things anymore.
我可不是不能变通的人
I'm nothing
if I'm not fIexibIe.
你什么意思，玛丽？
What are you saying,
Marie?
我们可以坐沙发上？
We can sit on the couch?
请便，弗兰克。
请吧
Be my guest, Frank.
Go ahead.
那么，我们可以坐那？
So, we can
reaIIy sit there?
在真正的沙发上？
On the actuaI couch?
坐吧，好好享受
Go ahead, enjoy.
- 你先
- 呃呃
- You first.
- Huh-uh.
坐下行不行？
这是个沙发！
WouId you sit?
It's a couch!
看到了，黛比拉？
我可以变的
You see, Debra?
I can change.
我可以放手
I can Iet go.
- 面料不错，是不是？
- 非常好
- It's nice fabric, isn't it?
- It's very nice.
我觉得淘气
I feeI
a IittIe naughty.
等不及到夏天了
Can't wait tiII summer.
嘿――嘿，你呢，玛丽？
Hey-- hey, what
about you, Marie?
你这么多年累死累活的做卫生，
You spent aII these years
knocking yourseIf out cIeaning,
你应该享受享受
you shouId enjoy this.
说得对
That's right.
谢谢你，黛比拉
Thank you, Debra.
请让一下
Excuse me.
真舒服
This is nice.
你做什么？！
What are you doing?!
看你做了什么！
你高兴了？
Look what you did!
Are you happy now?
她让我紧张。
臭着眼瞪我！
She was making me nervous.
Giving me the skunk eye!
我们要把套子遮上！
We're putting
the pIastic back on!
不！不！
你们干什么？
No! No!
What are you doing?
- 你不明白！
- 你们想就套上吧
- You don't understand!
- Put the cover back if you want.
只要你们快乐
Do whatever
makes you happy.
我的家人是第一位的
My famiIy comes first.
你们也许会想
You might want to take
those cushions outside
先把垫子拿出去抖抖
and shake them out first.
我来教你们做
I'II show you how.
来吧。把渣子抖下来
Come on.
We'II shake 'em out.
能打点下薯片吗，黛比拉？
能把它们捡起来吗？
Can you do the chips, Debra?
Can you pick them up?
是的，没问题
Yeah, no probIem.
天哪
Jeez.
嘿，歇会啦
Hey, take a break aIready.
天，这东西多爽呀！
Man, isn't this
thing great?
我希望他们做做
能骑着的那种
I wish they made one
if these you couId ride.
给，给你做的肉块三明治
Here, I made you
a meatIoaf sandwich.
哦，谢谢
Oh, thanks.
今天白天多数地区晴，
MostIy sunny skies today,
伴随轻柔东风。
预计最高气温52度
with brisk easterIy winds.
Expect a high near 52.
晚间依然晴朗，
最低气温41度
CIear tonight,
with a Iow near 41.
明天……
Tomorrow...
你看，咱们的老吸尘器
就做不了这个
You see, our oId
vacuum couIdn't do this.
jojoba
yettoreturn@hotmail.com